<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: programming | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/programming/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-09T16:50:20-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On Reading Code: Assume Positive Intent]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/09/29/on-wtf-moments-assume-positive-intent/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-29T20:33:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/09/29/on-wtf-moments-assume-positive-intent</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every software developer out there in the real world has likely come across what's known as a WTF.  In layman's terms it means coming across code that makes no sense, either through bad techniques, design or just unnecessary 'cleverness'.  See <a href="http://thedailywtf.com/">here</a> for some funny examples.</p>

<p>In my early days as a professional developer I used to work up a little fit when I read stuff that made no sense at all.  But nowadays I'm pretty zen about it.  I'm reminded of this quote by Indra Nooyi, CEO of Pepsi.</p>

<blockquote><p>My father was an absolutely wonderful human being. From him I learned to always assume positive intent. Whatever anybody says or does, assume positive intent. You will be amazed at how your whole approach to a person or problem becomes very different. When you assume negative intent, you're angry. If you take away that anger and assume positive intent, you will be amazed. Your emotional quotient goes up because you are no longer almost random in your response. You don't get defensive. You don't scream. You are trying to understand and listen because at your basic core you are saying, "Maybe they are saying something to me that I'm not hearing." So "assume positive intent" has been a huge piece of advice for me.</p></blockquote>

<p>The takeaway for me is that if you get angry or negative about code, you're wasting energy on something that's outside of your control.  I've seen developers go on long rants about someone else's work, only to later recant when they missed some detail.  It's just not worth it.  Instead, apply that energy toward fully understanding the problem space and the developer's intentions.  In the end, maybe the code is just bad and you're no better off.  But you'll be happier and more sane if you assume positive intent.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Prefer Enums as Parameters]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/09/17/prefer-enums-as-parameters/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-17T23:04:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/09/17/prefer-enums-as-parameters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post goes along with the previous one about <a href="http://kwangbkim.com/blog/2013/09/08/named-parameters-for-readability/">named parameters</a>.  I was re-reading some old notes from <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Effective-Java-Edition-Joshua-Bloch/dp/0321356683/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1379471724&amp;sr=8-1&amp;keywords=effective+java">Effective Java</a> when I came across a little snippet about why enums are preferable as parameter types over things like booleans or strings.</p>

<p>Take this example:</p>

<pre><code>public int someFormula(int value, bool isFarenheight) {
  // do some stuff...
}
</code></pre>

<p>This method signature isn't egregious, but there are a few issues.  The first is that an assumption is made that a celsius value will be passed in if isFarenheight = false.  It's probably what the API is expecting, but who knows for sure?  I suppose the parameter could be renamed to <em>isFarenheightOrCelsius</em>.  But say, for whatever reason, a new degree type needs to be included.  Now the situation becomes more complicated.  The API developer will probably have to create a brand new method with a different name, or do a one-off overload that'll make things even more confusing for the client developer.</p>

<p>In short, when in doubt try to prefer enums as parameter types.  It's more readable for the developer and extensible for future changes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Named Parameters for Readability]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/09/08/named-parameters-for-readability/"/>
    <updated>2013-09-08T18:11:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/09/08/named-parameters-for-readability</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here's a nice, <a href="http://mat-mcloughlin.net/2013/08/27/using-named-parameters-for-constants.html">short post</a> I enjoyed about how to make your code more readable.  I think this is particular useful for the languages out there without a big IDE.  In .NET, using solid parameter names mitigates the usefulness of this because of intellisense.  But, overall I'll be trying to do this more in my own code.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
