<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: poetry | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/poetry/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-10-03T00:14:54-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Is Poetry Dead?]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/10/02/is-poetry-dead/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-02T23:06:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/10/02/is-poetry-dead</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read an <a href="wapost%20link">article</a> recently about poetry questioning if it's now a defunct, irrelevant art.  And though in the past few years I've gotten into poetry, I must admit there are some fair points in there.  In my own experience, I find some poems to be flat out boring.  Poems written by people quite famous and well praised in the academic/artistic community.  I can't help it, I wish I enjoyed them more.  But it feels like work just to get through it because the text is so densely filled with imageries, descriptions and abstractions.</p>

<p>Then one day, I read this poem and it got me thinking about all of the above.  It goes like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>Sometimes I cry when I'm alone<br/>
I cry because I'm on my own<br/>
The tears I cry R bitter and warm<br/>
They flow with life and take no form<br/>
I cry because my heart is torn<br/>
and I find it difficult 2 carry on<br/>
if I had an ear 2 confide in<br/>
I would cry among my treasured friends<br/>
But who do u know that stops that long<br/>
to help another carry on<br/>
The world moves fast and it would rather pass u by<br/>
than 2 stop and c what makes u cry<br/>
It's painful and sad and sometimes I cry<br/>
and no one cares about why.</p></blockquote>

<p>That's from Tupac Shakur in a collection of poems released in a book titled <a href="http://www.amazon.com/The-Rose-that-Grew-Concrete/dp/0671028456/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;qid=1380773049&amp;sr=8-2&amp;keywords=tupac">The Rose That Grew From Concrete</a>.  I really enjoyed reading all of his stuff.  The pieces are clean, minimalistic, thoughtful and easy to understand.</p>

<p>The poem above was one that stuck out to me.  I was never a big fan of Tupac, didn't know much about him and I wasn't into the 90s rap scene (though I did like <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nay31hvEvrY">Changes</a> a lot).  But in less than 15 lines of text I do feel like I know him a bit and have some perspective on his life.</p>

<p>In the end I think the days of big, famous poems and poetry are over.  But if words on a page can still help us relate to each other, well I think that's a timeless quality.  And on that note, maybe we can send some poetry to Congress as they <a href="http://www.cnn.com/2013/10/01/politics/government-shutdown/index.html">don't seem to care</a> for each other much these days.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
