<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: foreign labor | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/foreign-labor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-24T14:45:27-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Made in the USA]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/12/06/made-in-the-usa/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-06T21:55:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/12/06/made-in-the-usa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>"Made in the USA" seems to be all the rage these days.  For instance, today Apple announced that they'll start <a href="http://www.latimes.com/business/la-fi-apple-manufacturing-20121207,0,2720461.story">building Macs in the USA</a> again next year.  I think the underlying principle here is intuitive enough, there has been plenty of bad press regarding the conditions of foreign factories making US products.  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=M5uYCWVfuPQ">Nike</a> is another company that comes to mind.  The stories detail sweatshop conditions, minimal salaries and long hours, in some cases even leading to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Foxconn_suicides">suicides</a>.</p>

<p>Imagine having to walk into these factories every day, working super long shifts for little pay and no prospects for growth.  Miserable right?  So the consensus becomes let's take away those awful jobs and bring them back to the US where they belong.</p>

<p>The problem is, what we think are horrible conditions (which they are) are locally considered really, really good in comparison to the domestic competition.  According to  <a href="http://www.theatlantic.com/magazine/archive/2012/12/mr-china-comes-to-america/309160/?single_page=true">this</a> nice article at the Atlantic :</p>

<blockquote><p>If you are looking for the most-gruesome factory conditions in China, you don’t go to a  multinational giant like Foxconn, which has to deal with Western customers and pay at least some attention to appearances and laws. You go instead to the small, ramshackle, often unregulated workshops, often away from the big cities, where conditions are as inefficient and sometimes as unsafe as they were when China was just beginning to industrialize.</p></blockquote>

<p>I agree with the overall sentiment of making products domestically.  It is an altruistic notion that we demand our products be made in safe, fair environments.  But if our long term goal is to help foreign countries improve their own working conditions, simply taking jobs away and moving them back to the US may be counterproductive.  As in, it lowers the overall supply of jobs, thereby weakening the bargaining power of the labor force, and making it easier for the sweatshops that we hate so much to subsist.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
