<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: startups | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/startups/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-30T23:55:41-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sum Zero Silicon Valley]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/silicon-valley-and-the-timeshare-model/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T23:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/silicon-valley-and-the-timeshare-model</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week I've been reading a lot of material on <a href="http://daltoncaldwell.com/">Dalton Caldwell's</a> blog.  It's a tiny bit Jerry Maguire-ish but over and over again I find myself nodding my head in agreement.  The latest hot topic has been the recent changes to Twitter, presumably in an attempt to gain a better position to monetize their business.</p>

<p>I think there is a fundamental flaw in the tech to marketing business model.  By saying tech to marketing, I mean a company who starts off as a tech company to attract users, who then changes to a marketing company to make money once they reach critical mass.  It's happened to Facebook, and now it's happening to Twitter.</p>

<p>There's nothing wrong when a business tries to make money.  But something seems a bit dubious about the whole process.  It's kind of like one of those free timeshare weekend getaways.  Seems like a nice deal, until you're subjected to 8 hours of pitches from salesman.  Yes, those salesman were within their right to do whatever.  After all, it's not like you're paying for anything.  But it still leaves a bad taste in your mouth doesn't it?</p>

<p>It's the same kind of idea with some of these tech companies.  They've attained users who've been attracted to their free service.  But now to monetize the business the focus changes from pleasing the users to pleasing the advertisers or sponsors.  It creates a sum zero relationship because it's near impossible to keep either happy without angering the other.  In the end the advertisers are the ones paying, so they are the ones who are catered to.  Meanwhile, users and third party developers slowly get more and more annoyed until a new free service comes along and everyone joins that and the business goes bust.  Presumably the process will repeat itself.</p>

<p>Granted, not all companies have problems with this model.  <a href="http://www.stackexchange.com">StackExchange</a> offers an amazing product, is free and ad supported and is doing just fine thank you.</p>

<p>Going back to Twitter, I've subscribed to <a href="http://join.app.net">App.Net</a>, Dalton Caldwell's potential alternative.  Imagine the best of Twitter: clean, no ads, completely user focused, all for four bucks a month.  But it needs to raise $500k by August 14th and it doesn't seem like they're going to make it.  But we can all dream can't we?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
