<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nintendo | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/nintendo/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-06T22:12:15-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Childhood Nostalgia: NES Cartridge Cleaning]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/nes/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T14:20:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/nes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>There was an <a href="http://www.mentalfloss.com/blogs/archives/142550">article</a> the other day analyzing the effectiveness of blowing into NES cartridges.  The conclusion they came to was that blowing did not help at all and any perceived improvement was due to the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Placebo">placebo effect</a>.</p>

<p>To which I can only reply:
<img src="/images/No.jpeg" alt="" /></p>

<p>Ok, so they're probably right, technically.  But aside from playing the Nintendo, the only thing better was trying to make the thing work.  Which it didn't half the time.  As a kid, getting an NES was like the adolescent version of your first car.  It was old, beat up and incredibly unreliable.  But when you were able to cruise around for a while (before it broke down at the worst possible time) was it not the best thing ever?</p>

<p>In my opinion, blowing into those cartridges was all part of the NES experience.  It was like a bonding ritual.  Where I grew up you were not cool until you had a routine that seemed to work more often than not.  You were also encouraged to try special moves during times of crisis.  If you could make an NES work long enough to beat Zelda and get through Contra (with or without the <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Konami_Code">Konami Code</a>) you were basically a legend.</p>

<p>I think back to what it would have been like to sit around the NES, monotonically resetting the cartridge, hoping for a good connection.  It may have made the system work better and for longer.  But ironically, it would have been a whole lot less fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
