<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: taxes | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/taxes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-09T16:50:20-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[IRS: You owe $22,948]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/irs-you-owe-23-dollars/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T14:12:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/irs-you-owe-23-dollars</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Imagine lounging around on a typical weekend afternoon browsing through paper mail when you come upon this nice letter, courtesy of our IRS.</p>

<p><img src="/images/letter.jpg" title=" " alt="" /></p>

<p>Accurate portrayal of my reaction can be found <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NefM2gVo9mw">here</a>.</p>

<p>The photo below is a sample of what they view as unclaimed income.</p>

<p><img src="/images/statement.png" title=" " alt="" /></p>

<p>The first two items are from when I was playing around with algorithmic trading.  I wrote a little bit about it <a href="http://kwangbkim.com/blog/2012/08/26/tried-algo-trading/">here</a>.  Except of course, I <em>lost</em> money.  Instead they are claiming that every single purchase I made was pure profit.  Put in other words, they claim I bought every security for nothing and so when I sold it everything was income.  If only there was a way!</p>

<p>The bottom two Vanguard items assert that I made $10,500 from US tax exempt treasuries (low risk, low return government bonds)  Also, emphasis belongs to <em>tax exempt</em>, how can you be taxed on a tax exempt security?.  But aside from that suppose  it were taxed, let's say those funds averaged %3 annual returns this year (a generous approximation).  That would mean that I have over $350,000 invested between the two funds.  Hm let me check my accounts... nope :)</p>

<p>While I'm hopeful this will all get sorted out neatly, I'm having trouble understanding exactly how this happened.  For full disclosure I used TurboTax, which is usually a breeze especially when your tax situation isn't complex (i.e. no income other than from your job).  So perhaps something happened there, but either way the next few weeks will be interesting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
