<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: orson welles | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/orson-welles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-09-29T21:17:50-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Orson Welles, Biased Bios]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/01/08/orson-welles/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-08T21:51:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/01/08/orson-welles</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I fully admit I know little to nothing about art, or any of its related businesses.  But I'm particularly interested in learning about the process and thought that goes into making it.  As a software developer I think there's a certain connection between the two.  Because whether you're painting, making a movie, or creating an algorithm, you start from a point of ambiguity.  That is, you start off with a 'blank sheet', and if things go well somehow your head fills it with whatever you were looking for.</p>

<p>So, while randomly perusing the local library last month, I picked this book up on a whim.  My knowledge on Welles prior to reading this book was quite minimal, I had vaguely heard of him and knew he was involved in films somehow.</p>

<p><img src="/images/higham.JPG" title=" " alt="" /></p>

<p>What really jumped out of the pages was Welles's staggering work ethic.  He would consistently take on multiple director positions, radio shows and movie roles at the same time.  At certain points his schedule bordered on insanity.  He would fly off to film a few scenes of a movie for a few weeks, leave to a completely different continent to direct some more scenes of a different movie, then leave to act in a role of a third movie in order to make some money to help pay off the costs of the first movie.  Confused yet?</p>

<p>For all his artistic genius Welles's lacked some of those necessary "soft" skills needed to be successful.  By repeatedly delivering films late and constantly going over budget, he became untrusted by traditional movie studios.  Without the discipline to hit deadlines or spend wisely, Welles's ended up having to take on many roles in movies to help pay for the costs of the films he was directing.</p>

<p>Unfortunately there wasn't much insight on the details and thought processes of Welles's films.  The main thing I took away from a software point of view, is that when everyone is great at coding, it'll be those ancillary soft skills that determine who the best employees are.  Because when everyone is smart, only those who can communicate well and have the discipline to ship things on time will be the most sought after.</p>

<p>On a side note, over reading this bio the author was quite content on downplaying the successes of Welles's while focusing on the negatives and failures.  I had always assumed biographies were meant to be more scientific, portraying someone else's life in a completely bipartisan manner.  Whether money or contempt played a factor I don't know, but the whole thing just seemed a little odd.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
