<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: nyc | Kwang B. Kim]]></title>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/categories/nyc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-17T17:30:32-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kwang B. Kim]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Changes]]></title>
    <link href="http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/08/06/changes/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-06T20:35:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://kwangbkim.github.com/blog/2013/08/06/changes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is long overdue, but the past few months have been hectic.  The main reason being I've transferred from my company's Hartford, CT office to Manhattan.</p>

<p>The moving process itself was quite smooth and went without a hitch.  If you're thinking of moving here and want to chat definitely shoot me an email.  In the meantime here's a couple of things and thoughts that might help.</p>

<h4>Money</h4>

<p>Dollar wise, the cost of living increase isn't all that bad, provided you can make a few sacrifices like living with a roommate and in a smaller place.  After getting a cost of living adjustment from my company, I'd probably end up making more money if I lived the same lifestyle that I did in CT.  But therein lies the problem, because there's lots to do around here, and being stuck in a tiny apartment isn't a lot of fun.  And it seems you can't walk out  the door without spending $20.</p>

<h4>Finding a place</h4>

<p>I suggest starting out on this site at <a href="https://www.airbnb.com/locations/new-york">airbnb</a>.  Picking out a neighborhood that suits your needs and personality makes a big difference in your NYC experience.  From there if you can narrow down your living area to a few places, you'll have an easier time filtering stuff on Craigslist, which is still the go to for roommates and open places.</p>

<h4>Energy</h4>

<p>There really is something to say about the energy here.  A while ago I could scarcely make it past 10pm without having thoughts of going to bed.  Late nights are a regular occurrence now, whether that be working or going out.</p>

<h4>Dirty old boroughs</h4>

<p>Between my bubble boy allergies, bad air quality and loathe for walking I immediately got sick upon arriving.  When you first get here try not to go overboard and do too much too fast.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
